cert.org 2018-02-02

# Legal | Privacy Statement | Privacy Statement for Data Collected Online

At the Software Engineering Institute (SEI), we value visitors to our  Service (as defined in the [Terms  of Use](http://www.sei.cmu.edu/legal/index.cfm)) and take your personal privacy seriously. We have  posted this privacy statement to inform you of our practices for handling the  data the SEI collects online via this Service. The Service site was created in  the United States and does not necessarily comply with laws of any other  country, so please review this statement before submitting any data though this  site. This privacy statement is incorporated into and subject to the [Terms of Use](http://www.sei.cmu.edu/legal/index.cfm).  Please direct any questions or comments regarding this statement to [privacy-info@sei.cmu.edu](mailto:privacy-info@sei.cmu.edu).

## Use of Cookies and Web Beacons

A cookie is a small text file containing information that a web site  transfers to your computer for recordkeeping purposes. We use cookies to  analyze traffic patterns on our site.

A web beacon is a transparent, 1-pixel image in .gif format that helps us  collect data about visitors viewing a web page -- for example, to count the  number of visitors to a page or to deliver a cookie to visitors' browsers when  they view that page. We may use web beacons on this site from time to time for  these and other purposes.

  Cookies and web beacons cannot give us access to your computer or to  information beyond what you provide to us. Disabling cookies in your browser  will prevent us from using cookies or web beacons to collect data about your  visit to our site, but you will still be able to view the publicly available  information on our web site. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies.  Consult your browser's manual or online help if you want information on  restricting or disabling the browser's handling of cookies. If you are using a  shared computer and you have cookies turned on, be sure to log off when you finish.

## Use of these technologies by  authorized third-party service providers

We may work with third-party companies, commonly known as service  providers, who are authorized to place third-party cookies, web beacons, or  similar technologies for storing information on our sites or in our services,  applications, and tools with our permission. These service providers help us to  provide you with a better, faster, and safer experience.

These service providers may use these technologies to help us deliver our  own content and advertising, and compile anonymous site metrics and analytics.  Third-party cookies are covered by the third parties' privacy policy.

For more information on third-party service providers that we use and how  to opt-out of them, please visit the following third party websites:

[ **How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps**](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)

[**Information   Obtained When You Visit Crazy Egg Client Websites**](https://www.crazyegg.com/privacy)  
  ([Crazy Egg Opt-out  instructions](https://www.crazyegg.com/opt-out))

## Collecting Your Personal  Information

Sometimes we ask you for information that personally identifies you (personal  information) so that you can perform actions on the SEI Web site (such as  accessing certain parts of the site, contacting us, or requesting information).  This personal information may include name, email address, postal address,  country, and telephone number, and may also include additional information when  necessary—for example, if you choose to take actions like these:

  * register for SEI courses, programs, or  events
 
  * contact us
 
  * volunteer to complete surveys or  participate in polls
 
  * enter a promotional program or activity
 
  * request newsletters, promotional emails,  printed materials, etc.
 
  * purchase merchandise

## Choice Regarding Collection of  Personal Information

You may choose not to provide us with personal information, in which case  you may not be able to perform actions on the SEI Web site like those described  above.

## Links to Other Sites

Links to third-party Web sites may appear within the SEI Web site for your  convenience and information. Using these links will cause you to access Web  sites that are not part of the SEI Web site, even though they may contain SEI  logos, information, etc. The SEI is not responsible for the content or privacy  practices of other sites. We suggest that you carefully review the privacy  policies of each site you visit.

## How We Use and Share Information  Collected

We do not connect the personal and impersonal information we collect on the  Service.

We may provide third parties with aggregated impersonal information  collected from SEI Web site users.

We may use personal information collected from you to—among other  things—respond to you, contact you, or provide you with information or  services. We occasionally contract with other organizations to provide services  such as packaging, mailing, or delivering merchandise, materials, information,  etc.; processing orders for merchandise; and processing course and event  registrations. We provide such organizations with only the information they  need to deliver such services.

When you give us your personal information online, we will not sell, trade,  or rent this personal information to third parties or share it without your  consent, other than in the situations described above. The SEI does not intend  to reveal personal information except as outlined in this privacy statement.  Your personal information may be stored and processed in the United States or  any other country where the SEI, its affiliates, or its agents are located.

The SEI or Carnegie Mellon University may disclose the personal information  of individual users if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief  that such action is necessary, as when conforming to the edicts of the law,  complying with a legal process served on the SEI or its Web site, acting in  urgent circumstances involving personal or public safety, or protecting and  defending the rights or property of the SEI and its Web site.

## Children's Privacy

Protecting children's privacy is extremely important to us. The SEI Web  site is not intended for the use of or designed to attract the attention of  children, and we do not collect personal information from anyone we know to be  under age 13 without requesting parental consent.

## Your Consent

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this  information by the SEI. If there are any changes to the terms of this statement,  the revised version will be posted on this Web page so that you are always  aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what  circumstances we disclose it.

## Your Ability to Access and  Update Personal Information

If you have questions about the personal information you have submitted via  the SEI Web site, please contact [privacy-info@sei.cmu.edu](mailto:privacy-info@sei.cmu.edu).
